Bhavik Gilbert

Software Engineer

Contact



Bhaviklob@hotmail.com

+447405805628

Links



@Bhavik Gilbert

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhavik -gilbert-2349631a9/



@Bhavik Gilbert

https://github.com/Bhavik-Gilbert?tab=repositories



Portfolio Site

https://bhavik-gilbert.github.io/

Skillset

Python, PHP, SQL, Java, C#, JavaScript, VB.net, R-Studio

Education

GCSE - St. Aloysius R.C College

Computer Science, Mathematics,

Further Mathematics, Business,

Biology, Chemistry, Physics,

Religious Education, Spanish

English Literature/ Language

2014-2021

A-Levels - Leyton VI Form College

Mathematics, Economics, Physics, Computer Science

2019-2021

University - King's College

BSc(Hons) Computer Science

2021 - 2024

Interests

Volleyball, Badminton, Travel

References

Timothy.Osadiya@leyton.ac.uk

Profile

Driven by avid interest in Tech, I've come across a range of experiences in several positions within different sectors to help expand my knowledge, trying find my footholds within the industry. To this end, I've dabbled within several fields varying between: data analysis, game development, machine learning, web development and database systems.

Proceeding forward, I want to further develop my knowledge around the field of computer software outside the reach of personal projects, providing a tangible output into the industry, bettering my problem solving and algorithmic thinking in the process.

Work Experience

Leyton VI Form College (09/2021-Current) - 'Computer Science Mentor'

Advising students in aspects of their A-Level coursework. Usage includes PHP, JavaScript, SQL, C#, and Python. Teaching students how to correctly design, document and develop software systems, focusing highly on web development and database systems. Other areas include: unity 3D game development, and python 2D game development and python AI development.

Funtech (07/2021 - 08/2021) - 'Computer Science Teacher'

Teaching students aged 6-16 theory and practical application of computer science changing each week. My courses included: AI and Machine Learning (TensorFlow/PIL/Google Vision/Numpy), Robotics Cyber Security(Kali Linux), 3D Game Development (UE4) and Python Development

Procedural/OOP(Tkinter). The role required the necessary communication and organisational skills to engage and manage students, ensuring they both enjoy themselves and learn effectively, joined with calm and logical thinking to manage any unforeseen issues that may occur.

Projects

For a full list of my projects visit: https://bhavik-gilbert.github.io/Projects.html

Ecosystem Simulator

Simulator with GUI(concurrent Executors, Swing, JPanel)

Partner project revolving around the creation of an ecosystem simulator. Includes animals, plants, weather effects, disease and time of day, dictating animal actions and effecting action probability. Functional and OOP implementation using Java class structure alongside lambdas and executor class to make use of multi-thread operations to speed up performance where possible. GUI displays selected actors in ecosystem field alongside details on the current state of the simulation such as population figures and current weather.

Facial Recognition Login System

Python
AI with GUI and Database System(Tkinter/PIL/CV2/DeepFace(tensorflow)/MYSQL Connector)

The system once given the username of the user that wants to login, will take a picture and check it against all available images in the system under that username, if it matches over 80% of the images in the system, the image taken is then added to the list for future login purposes, thereby allowing the system to develop and become more accurate the more times a user logs in. Signup functionality with validation included.

Photography Booking & Management System

PHP/SQL/HTML/JavaScript

The development of a booking system using SQL Databases. Feature Overview: account creation(validated), account editing, secure login (hashing, salting, captcha), booking, after booking editing, encrypted card saving, inbuilt email contact, pdf booking receipt, graphical report of sales, imagery portfolio slideshow.

Additional Certifications

- Foreage -> JPMorgan Software Engineering Virtual Experience
- Springpod -> Deloitte Consulting Work Experience
- Springpod Technology Virtual Work Experience
- DofE Bronze & Silver
- KCL Professional Skills for a Globalised World
- OFQUAL Open Awards Entry Level Award in Employability and Professional Development (Entry 3)(RQF)
- OpenLearn Course Technological innovation: a resource-based view
- OpenLearn CourseDesign thinking
- OpenLearn Course An introduction to software development